MIMOUN JAKHROUTI

Data Scientist

- **** +2126 41 22 69 21
- www.linkedin.com/in/mimoun-jakhrouti
- Casablanca

- @ mimounjakhrouti@gmail.com
- https://mimoun-jakhrouti.github.io



SUMMARY

I am a highly motivated Data Scientist with a Master's Degree in Statistical Modelling, coupled with experience in Data Analysis. My academic background and practical experience have equipped me with advanced analytical skills. I excel in applying Machine Learning to solve real-world challenges in business contexts.

EXPERIENCE

Junior Data Analyst

ThinkONE Research & Consulting

iii 07/2023 - Present ♀ Casablanca

Worked on a variety of Quantitative Analysis and Consulting projects, contributing to improved revenue and heightened customer satisfaction.

- Designed and maintained dynamic dashboards for monitoring quotas in six African countries, aiding in the oversight and updating of field data.
- Proposed and enhanced data quality management processes, restoring the integrity and validity of KPIs.
- Integrated and scripted new survey analysis techniques for NPS & Satisfaction projects, ensuing in more accurate and meaningful insights.

Data Analyst Intern

ThinkONE Research & Consulting

iii 01/2023 - 07/2023 ♀ Casablanca

Contributed to the automation of data and insight tasks and processes, resulting in increased efficiency and time-saving benefits.

- Designed and implemented R scripts for the Data team, leading to a 30% increase in data cleaning efficiency and data visualization customization.
- Developed and maintained VBA scripts to automate dashboard construction used by the Insight team, resulting in 70% time savings.
- Built and deployed an online HR platform using JS and PHP, helping to track and manage employees' information more effectively.

EDUCATION

Master's Degree: Economic Analysis and Modelling

Mohammed V University iii 2020 - 2022 ♀ Rabat

Bachelor's Degree: Economics and Management

Mohammed First University

iii 2017 - 2020 ♀ Oujda

LANGUAGES

Arabic	Native	French	Proficient		
English	Proficient				

STRENGTHS



Strong Analytical Skills

Tackled complex data analysis projects resulting in increased cost savings.



Adaptability

Quickly learned new tools or technologies, and adjusted to evolving business needs.



Attention to Detail

Committed to accuracy, strived for the highest level of quality in my work.

SKILLS

Hard Skills

Python	R	SQL	L Tableau		Git		
PowerBI	HTN	/L	CSS	JS	PHP		
Data Analysis Statistical Modelling							
Machine Learning Deep Learning							
Soft Skills							
Problem Solving			Critical Thinking				
Communication		C	Collaboration				
Creativity	In	novat	ion	Curio	sity		

CERTIFICATION

Data Science Professional Certificate

IBM, 2021

Machine Learning and Reinforcement Learning in Finance Specialization

NYU Tandon School of Engineering, 2021

Communication and Interpersonal Skills at Work

University of Leeds and Institute of Coding, 2020